Nicole Soeng

253-230-5082

nicole.soeng@outlook.com

Virginia Beach, VA

linkedin.com/in/nicole-soeng

github.com/nicoleSoeng

% nicolesoeng.github.io

ABOUT ME

Junior web developer with experience writing clean and efficient code to create responsive, well-designed web applications.

I am a highly motivated worker with a passion for working with clients to develop user-friendly interactive websites and applications. I have a background in UI/UX analysis along with a proficiency in scripting languages.

SKILLS

- HTML5
- CSS₃
- JavaScript, jQuery
- Git, GitHub
- PHP, SQL
- Microsoft Office Suite

CERTIFICATIONS

Microsoft Technology Associate 98-375: HTML5 Application Development Fundamentals May 2022

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Certificate

Texas A&M International University

Master of Public Administration

Evans School of Public Affairs, University of Washington 2009-2011

Bachelor of Arts, Sociology

Western Washington University 2005-2007

EXPERIENCE

Internet Search Analyst
RaterLabs, July 2016 - Present

Analyze and rate quality and accuracy of web content.

- Evaluate fitness, accuracy, and quality of web pages
- Rate pages based on quality of web content and UI/UX design
- Analyze web content for reliability of sources/information

Policy Analyst, Internship
League of Education Voters, August 2010 – June 2011

Co-authored a proposal for the Washington State Senate Early Learning Technical Working Group to expand prekindergarten access in WA.

- Compiled statistics and financial data on prekindergarten benefits
- Gathered qualitative data through interviews with experts
- Conducted a cost-benefit analysis of prekindergarten roll-out options

Research Assistant, Internship
Alliance for a Just Society, June 2010 – August 2010

Wrote and edited Native Health Underfunded & Promises Unfulfilled: The Importance of Investing in the Indian Health Service.

Mentor Program Coordinator

Communities in Schools of Federal Way, April 2008 – April 2009

Managed volunteer mentoring program, recruited and trained mentors and developed program promotional and training materials, created and updated mentor databases.